A Guide to the Pimmit Hills Citizens Association Records, 1952-2012
Virginia Room, Fairfax County Public Library
The Pimmit Hills Citizens Association Records, 1952-2012
Fairfax County Public Library
MSS 05-15
4.0 linear feet
The Pimmit Hills Citizens Association Records consists of 4.0 linear feet and spans the years 1952-2012, and contains minute books, meeting attendance records, telephone directories, newsletters, newspaper clippings, a scrapbook, and other administrative papers.
Pimmit Hills Citizens Association
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None
Acquisition Information
The Pimmit Hills Citizens Association donated the bulk of the collection through the efforts of Patricia F. Donahue in May 2018. Newspaper clippings and early PHCA papers were donated by Nan Netherton at unknown earlier date. Janice H. Vranich donated the 1956 deed and bill of sale for her parents’ Pimmit Hills house at 325 Burnside Court in August 2018.
Historical and Biographical Information
Residents of the Pimmit Hills neighborhood, a subdivision of 1,675 small inexpensive houses built by George Offutt in Fairfax County from 1950-1958, organized the Pimmit Hills Citizens Association on March 28, 1951. The purpose of the association was to solve and improve many of the neighborhood’s problems, provide a forum for discussion, and to overall make Pimmit Hills a better place to live. Almost seventy years later, the association continues to be active.
Scope and Content
The Pimmit Hills Citizens Association Records consists of 4.0 linear feet and spans the years 1952-2012, and contains minute books, meeting attendance records, telephone directories, newsletters, newspaper clippings, a scrapbook, and other administrative papers. Subjects include the history of Pimmit Hills, Virginia.
Series 1: Administrative Records, Boxes 1-4
This series contains PHCA administrative records including minute books, meeting attendance records, a scrapbook, telephone directories, newspaper clippings, and other administrative files and papers. Also included is the original 1956 Pimmit Hills deed and bill of sale for Virgil and Florence Holtgrave, who resided at 325 Burnside Court.
Series 2: Newsletters, 1952-2012, Boxes 4-8
This series contains the newsletters that the PHCA published to keep residents informed about community news, meetings, and projects. PHCA first issued the Pimmit Hills Newsletter in 1952, and later renamed it the Pimmit Hills Dispatch in 1962.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
None
None
Index Terms
Falls Church (Va.) - History; Pimmit Hills (Va.) - History; Pimmit Hills Citizens Association
Container List
- Series 1: Administrative Records, 1952-2004
  - Minute Book, 1958 June-1963 June (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minute Book, 1966 December-1963 September (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minute Book, 1967 January-1974 June (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook on Pimmit Hills Street Light Fiesta, June 1, 1963, 1963, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Record Book, PHCA Attendance Record, 1966 September-1972 January (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Record Book, PHCA Attendance Record, 1972 February-1974 June (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Record Book, PHCA Attendance Record, 1974 September-1976 June (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Record Book, PHCA Attendance Record, 1976 September-1985 December (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Pimmit Hills Telephone Directory, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Pimmit Hills Telephone Directory, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Pimmit Hills Telephone Directory, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Pimmit Hills Telephone Directory, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Pimmit Hills Telephone Directory, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Pimmit Hills Telephone Directory, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Pimmit Hills Citizens Association Directory, Undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Advertising - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1961-2005 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Articles of Incorporation and By-laws, 1992-2004 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Bulk Mailing - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2001-2004 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Constitution, 1954-1962 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Executive Committee Meetings and Special Meetings, 1957-1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Financial Reports, 1954-1956 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Master Plan for the Leesburg-Shenandoah Interchange Area, 1963 May (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Membership and Volunteer lists, 1954-2004 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Newspaper clippings Re: Pimmit Hills, 1952-1955, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Newspaper clippings Re: Pimmit Hills, 1977-2002 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Parks, 1961, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - PHCA Capital Beltway HOT lanes handout, 2004 March 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - PHCA Neighborhood Watch official manual, Undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Pimmit Hills Homecoming Program, 2000 October 21 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Pimmit Hills Street Guide, Undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Position Paper of the PHCA on the Rezoning Applications B-651 & B-652 of Gail E. and Mary E. Boggs before the Fairfax County Board of Supervisors, Wednesday March 20, 1968 2:30 p.m., 1968 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Quality of Life survey, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Tickets, St. Patrick's Day Dance, Vienna Fire Hall, 1962 March 10 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Website, 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Deed and Bill of Sale for Virgil and Florence Holtgrave, 325 Burnside Court, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series 2: Newsletters, 1952-2012
  - The Pimmit Hills Newsletter, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - The Pimmit Hills Newsletter, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - The Pimmit Hills Newsletter, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - The Pimmit Hills Newsletter, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - The Pimmit Hills Newsletter, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1978 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1995-1996 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 1999 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2001 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2003 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2006-2010 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Pimmit Hills Dispatch, 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 11)